<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" >

<channel><title><![CDATA[Liberty and Belonging in America - Blog]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/blog]]></link><description><![CDATA[Blog]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 09:27:15 -0700</pubDate><generator>Weebly</generator><item><title><![CDATA[Journeying inward and northward (Day 11)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/blog/journeying-inward-and-northward-day-11]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/blog/journeying-inward-and-northward-day-11#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 04:03:12 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/blog/journeying-inward-and-northward-day-11</guid><description><![CDATA[    Click the image above to see more photos    From one island to the threshold of another (I may be saying the same thing a week from now, as I prepare to depart north haven and return home to O&rsquo;ahu). Em and I took the ferry back to Portland to meet Em&rsquo;s partner for an unbelievably timed meditation circle for people of color. One of the women in the circle described her experience of Maine as something she didn&rsquo;t realize she needed. My experience of the POC meditation practic [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><div class="wsite-image wsite-image-border-none " style="padding-top:10px;padding-bottom:10px;margin-left:0;margin-right:0;text-align:center"> <a href='https://photos.app.goo.gl/91rTgoKQWR3UtgpZ6'> <img src="http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/uploads/1/2/6/4/126456576/p374.png" alt="Picture" style="width:auto;max-width:100%" /> </a> <div style="display:block;font-size:90%">Click the image above to see more photos </div> </div></div>  <div class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;">From one island to the threshold of another (I may be saying the same thing a week from now, as I prepare to depart north haven and return home to O&rsquo;ahu). Em and I took the ferry back to Portland to meet Em&rsquo;s partner for an unbelievably timed meditation circle for people of color. One of the women in the circle described her experience of Maine as something she didn&rsquo;t realize she needed. My experience of the POC meditation practice was something I knew I needed, particular for the part of the journey that was about to begin, and it really could not have dropped out of the sky at a better time.</div>  <div>  <!--BLOG_SUMMARY_END--></div>  <div class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;">We ended up staying an hour later than we had planned &mdash; after the meditation, the group shared many threads of conversation, questions (including the ones that have been driving this journey for me), stories, and tears. When we finally did depart, I learned that Roland&rsquo;s (the man guiding the meditation) parents were Filipino physicians in Milwaukee at the same time my parents were in medical school / residency there. We resolved to figure out if they knew each other.<br /><br />Em&rsquo;s partner Ana is from the Rio Grande Valley, my home &ldquo;town&rdquo;. That&rsquo;s a surprising thing to encounter anywhere, much less in a corner of the US seemingly as far away from South Texas as it is from Hawaii (ok, thst might be a bit of a stretch). Reflecting on the dynamics of the place where we both came from on the drive to Rockland was full of useful insights and raised many more questions to site with. <br /><br />Importantly, though, it provided a grounding in my own experience of the relationship between people and place, tradition and meaning. Rockland was overrun with people in town for a blues festival &mdash; a musical tradition that immediately made me think of its roots in Congo Square where I had just been. Another connection to marvel at, but in this case, it also meant a lot of people crowding us out of our first choice for dinner. We did find a happy hour next door and got to enjoy some local fare and a nice summer night before I had to say goodbye to the ferry-friends who had gone as far as they could&rsquo;ve with me for this part of the journey. I&rsquo;d be making the trip to my final destination alone.<br /></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Port-landing in Maine (Day 10)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/blog/port-landing-in-maine-day-10]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/blog/port-landing-in-maine-day-10#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 04:00:49 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/blog/port-landing-in-maine-day-10</guid><description><![CDATA[    Click on the image to see more photos    This journey is about finding my stories, and my friend Em, who was my asylum-granting host in Portland, Maine, has been a part of that journey for me for longer than this trip. Em and I first connected, in Charlotte, where I had just spent the night at th 2nd annual Code for America Brigade Congress. At that conference, I presented my CfA fellowship work on the HART Sustainable Mobility Lab, which had at its heart, a reliance on stories to form the n [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><div class="wsite-image wsite-image-border-none " style="padding-top:10px;padding-bottom:10px;margin-left:0;margin-right:0;text-align:center"> <a href='https://photos.app.goo.gl/ngZa8TXgQDEV48wi7'> <img src="http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/uploads/1/2/6/4/126456576/p372.png" alt="Picture" style="width:auto;max-width:100%" /> </a> <div style="display:block;font-size:90%">Click on the image to see more photos</div> </div></div>  <div class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"> This journey is about finding my stories, and my friend Em, who was my asylum-granting host in Portland, Maine, has been a part of that journey for me for longer than this trip. Em and I first connected, in Charlotte, where I had just spent the night at th 2nd annual Code for America Brigade Congress. At that conference, I presented my CfA fellowship work on the HART Sustainable Mobility Lab, which had at its heart, a reliance on stories to form the networks and connections that underlie learning and innovation. My friendship with Em is a result of starting to live that idea &mdash; sharing stories of our parents and how we came to work on Civic Tech.</div>  <div>  <!--BLOG_SUMMARY_END--></div>  <div class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;">I&rsquo;m now very fortunate to serve with Em on Code for America&rsquo;s National Advisory Council which means we get to see each other several times a year. During one of those times, I mentioned I would be doing part of this learning excursion in Maine and they offered to meet up with me in Portland, ME where they lived and drive me up to Rockland (which is otherwise much harder to get to by small plane).<br /><br />For the summer, though, Em does not actually live in Portland,  but on an island off of its coast. After spending a day getting a glimpse of beautiful Portland and seeing a few of the places that contribute to its vibrancy, we boarded a ferry to Long Island where a grilled Halibut pasta, a newly installed record player, some readings of Joseph Campbell, and a moonlit tour of the island were waiting.<br /><br />What was really priceless was &mdash; as it has been throughout our friendship &mdash; the conversation, the thought partnership, and perspective widening that happens every time we talk or share. Em had just returned from the activism/organizing conference Netroots, was working on several political campaigns, and generally involved in interesting work in a special place. Add Portland and Long Island to the list of places and people I wish I didn&rsquo;t have to leave.<br /></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Storming out of Louisiana (Day 9)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/blog/storming-out-of-louisiana-day-9]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/blog/storming-out-of-louisiana-day-9#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 03:37:44 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/blog/storming-out-of-louisiana-day-9</guid><description><![CDATA[       I had hoped to stay in Houma and hunker down with my new friends through the coming storm. But with the storm trajectory and rain projections, it was looking increasingly likely that my scheduled Sunday flight would be disrupted. I spoke to the airline who, after a two hour wait to receive a callback, eagerly and efficiently found a new way for me out of New Orleans on Friday afternoon instead of Sunday Morning. The Louis Armstrong International Airport was full to the brim with other peo [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><div class="wsite-image wsite-image-border-none " style="padding-top:10px;padding-bottom:10px;margin-left:0;margin-right:0;text-align:center"> <a> <img src="http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/uploads/1/2/6/4/126456576/p369.png" alt="Picture" style="width:auto;max-width:100%" /> </a> <div style="display:block;font-size:90%"></div> </div></div>  <div class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;">I had hoped to stay in Houma and hunker down with my new friends through the coming storm. But with the storm trajectory and rain projections, it was looking increasingly likely that my scheduled Sunday flight would be disrupted. I spoke to the airline who, after a two hour wait to receive a callback, eagerly and efficiently found a new way for me out of New Orleans on Friday afternoon instead of Sunday Morning. The Louis Armstrong International Airport was full to the brim with other people doing the same thing.</div>  <div>  <!--BLOG_SUMMARY_END--></div>  <div class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;">I was sad to leave Louisiana more than a day early. There was already too much to see and do, too many wonderful people to be with in the little time I had. But the reports of flooding after I left seemed to confirm my decision making.<br /><br />I ended up spending the night in Charlotte with a close friend through my Code for America work. It was lovely to get to meet her family. Her husband, a Swede, is from a country formerly inhabited by the Sami people, for whom the university where my friend Imani did her Indigenous Journalism research that lead me to Louisiana was named. Getting to spend the night talking about indigenous people&rsquo;s of Europe, Swedish idioms, and the second amendment were unexpected surprise and appreciated accommodations for this particular climate refuge.<br /><br />I mad it to all of my flights successfully, which is to say the actual flying was successful. I noted two things about the experience at the airport, though. 1.) through all the chaos at the gates and security lines, there was still live jazz being played at restaurants and stages all throughout the airport. 2.) a group of people at my gate held an impromptu prayer circle. They were predominantly members of the Delta Sigma Theta Sorority, a historically black Greek organization, whose national convention at the Ernest Morial New Orleans convention center had just been cancelled due to weather to allow attendees to return safely to their families. The cancellation itself was a show of <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/marshallshepherd/2019/07/13/delta-sigma-theta-sororitys-response-to-tropical-storm-barry-is-a-model-to-follow/#408d67429009" target="_blank">leadership</a>. The would-be conventioners showed their values in who they invited (everyone) and who they included in their thoughts (everyone particularly those most vulnerable in the storm). <br /><br />Holding hands with those ladies and being part of that prayer was another unexpected blessing on this trip that I will never forget. When leadership was most needed, they showed us all how to do it.</div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Down the Bayou (Day 8)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/blog/down-the-bayou-day-8]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/blog/down-the-bayou-day-8#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 07:49:29 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/blog/down-the-bayou-day-8</guid><description><![CDATA[    Click on the image above to see more photos   In Houma, I was the beneficiary of bonafide Cajun hospitality. Jonathan hosted me at his home and then spent the day driving around with me to the sources of this hospitality, the places he grew up, and the wetlands that he fights for.      In the bayous, it&rsquo;s a little easier to see physical evidence of the conflict between human infrastructure in the built environment and the forces of nature. Flood gates, levees, elevated homes. It&rsquo; [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><div class="wsite-image wsite-image-border-none " style="padding-top:10px;padding-bottom:10px;margin-left:0;margin-right:0;text-align:center"> <a href='https://photos.app.goo.gl/UR9dPCUwvE3A89Mp8' target='_blank'> <img src="http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/uploads/1/2/6/4/126456576/p364.png" alt="Picture" style="width:auto;max-width:100%" /> </a> <div style="display:block;font-size:90%">Click on the image above to see more photos</div> </div></div>  <div class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;">In Houma, I was the beneficiary of bonafide Cajun hospitality. Jonathan hosted me at his home and then spent the day driving around with me to the sources of this hospitality, the places he grew up, and the wetlands that he fights for.</div>  <div>  <!--BLOG_SUMMARY_END--></div>  <div class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;">In the bayous, it&rsquo;s a little easier to see physical evidence of the conflict between human infrastructure in the built environment and the forces of nature. Flood gates, levees, elevated homes. It&rsquo;s a place that is both well-adapted to water, and on the verge of being overrun by it.<br /><br />A bayou I learned is a waterway. Smaller than a river, but bigger than a stream, and deep enough to park commercial fishing boats. Communities along these waterways have changed with the times, for example: driving on roads as we did instead of traveling primarily by boat, but the entire coastline is disappearing. As the sea level is rising, the coast is sinking/compacting and eroding (with the leveed Mississippi River unable to deposit new silt to replace what is falling of the continental shelf).<br /><br />We visited Isle de Jean Charles, recognized through an appeal for federal funding assistance to relocate the communities there as America&rsquo;s first climate refugees. They are separated from the rest of the inland communities by a long coastal road that the state has indicat d they no longer have the resources to maintain. The residents of the community are primarily of native heritage, tribal members of the United Houma Nation and the Biloxi, Chitimacha, Choctaw. 2 days later, these residents would be rescued from their roofs by the national guard as Hurricane Barry hammered the area with storm surge and heavy rain.<br /><br />The bayous are beautiful, the culture is special, and the people are resilient and capable. Their way of life, as I was so blessed to experience would be a great loss to the world. Of the many things that Jonathan and I talked about, one was his work on folklore. He is working on a project to identify the aspects of culture that people in the wetlands communities would want their descendants 7 generations In the future to be able to access. They are taking those things and storing them in a metaphorical &ldquo;Trunk of Tradition&rdquo;. It seems likely that it won&rsquo;t be long before the time when the people of the Louisiana coast will have to take their trunk to a new place, and use its contents to adapt again to new conditions.</div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Flooding and Fleeing to Houma (Day 7)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/blog/flooding-and-fleeing-to-houma-day-79434055]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/blog/flooding-and-fleeing-to-houma-day-79434055#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 07:35:24 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/blog/flooding-and-fleeing-to-houma-day-79434055</guid><description><![CDATA[    Click on the image above to see more photos   The previous night, I had moved over to stay with Luana, Charisse, and Sabrina since their other friends had left, and they had some extra room in the apartment they had rented for the week. That night, as we were sleeping (or trying to) through the open window, I heard a constant drill of magnificent and powerful thunderclaps. One of my hopes had been to experience Louisiana as a place, and it was clear that someone got the message. When I final [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><div class="wsite-image wsite-image-border-none " style="padding-top:10px;padding-bottom:10px;margin-left:0;margin-right:0;text-align:center"> <a href='https://photos.app.goo.gl/n2LrpDrzZrFJYg5m9'> <img src="http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/uploads/1/2/6/4/126456576/p360.png" alt="Picture" style="width:auto;max-width:100%" /> </a> <div style="display:block;font-size:90%">Click on the image above to see more photos</div> </div></div>  <div class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"><span style="font-family: ".SFUIText"; font-size: 17pt;">The previous night, I had moved over to stay with Luana, Charisse, and Sabrina since their other friends had left, and they had some extra room in the apartment they had rented for the week. That night, as we were sleeping (or trying to) through the open window, I heard a constant drill of magnificent and powerful thunderclaps. One of my hopes had been to experience Louisiana as a place, and it was clear that someone got the message. When I finally woke up in the morning to move my car and prevent it from getting towed or ticketed on the street, I found it floorboard-deep in a river that wasn&rsquo;t there the previous night.</span><br /><span></span></div>  <div>  <!--BLOG_SUMMARY_END--></div>  <div class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"><span style="font-family: ".SFUIText"; font-size: 17pt;">With some help from the valet and all of the people on the street, I managed to get it across the street into a parking lot on higher ground. But it was evident that today was not going to go as planned.</span><br /><span></span> <span style="font-family: ".SFUIText"; font-size: 17pt;"></span><br /><br /><span></span> <span style="font-family: ".SFUIText"; font-size: 17pt;">It was the girls&rsquo; last day and we had planned to see parts of Treme, Marigny, and have one last brunch before dropping them off at the airport. Instead, we got a preview of storm life in a city below sea level and under assault by water from all directions. </span><br /><span></span> <span style="font-family: ".SFUIText"; font-size: 17pt;"></span><br /><br /><span></span> <span style="font-family: ".SFUIText"; font-size: 17pt;">I had had a number of activities and loose ends set up in New Orleans, but with the storm coming, it didn&rsquo;t seem like that was going to happen. I decided to head into Houma a day earlier than planned since i was going on a Bayou tour with Jonathan the next day anyway, and it would help me steer clear of the flooding in New Orleans. It ended up working out because Jessi was at the United Houma Nation office in Houma and I was able to meet her there and chat for a few hours with her and her colleague Betty over some moccasin making.</span><br /><span></span> <span style="font-family: ".SFUIText"; font-size: 17pt;"></span><br /><br /><span></span> <span style="font-family: ".SFUIText"; font-size: 17pt;">We were making moccasins for betty&rsquo;s son and friend who were dancing in an annual mass to st. ... the first and only canonized Native American saint. Jesse was about to leave for a trip that included some time at a convening of women at a Living Systems Conference and Betty would be heading out to teach a camp of environmentalist students about indigenous issues and the effects of climate change being felt in Louisiana. Both sounded amazing and brought up Purple Mai&rsquo;a as one of the organizations I thought was doing some of the most impactful work and thst I hoped they could connect with some day.</span><br /><span></span> <span style="font-family: ".SFUIText"; font-size: 17pt;"></span><br /><br /><span></span> <span style="font-family: ".SFUIText"; font-size: 17pt;">Having just arrived, I asked for recommendations for where to eat and where to stay. They were free to hang out for a quick dinner to explain how to eat Louisiana seafood (much needed and appreciated) and they said the hotels were all fine,  but I should probably check with Jonathan. </span><br /><span></span> <span style="font-family: ".SFUIText"; font-size: 17pt;"></span><br /><br /><span></span> <span style="font-family: ".SFUIText"; font-size: 17pt;">I did and Jonathan proved, as advertised, to be an amazing and accommodating host. After drinking all of the beer in his house and keeping him up until the early morning chatting, I reflected a bit on all of the connections between Louisiana and Hawaii, in this case the incomparable hospitality. </span><br /><span></span></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Whitney Plantation: The Story of American Slavery (Day 5)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/blog/the-whitney-plantation-the-story-of-american-slavery-day-57843891]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/blog/the-whitney-plantation-the-story-of-american-slavery-day-57843891#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 07:30:27 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/blog/the-whitney-plantation-the-story-of-american-slavery-day-57843891</guid><description><![CDATA[     Click on image above to see more photos   A few days ago while we were taking a rest at Essence Fest, Kimberly brought out a pamphlet advertising the Whitney Plantation. She had heard about it previously and had been interested in going for a while. I had not heard of it, nor had I really contemplated going on any tours as part of this excursion, but all of the accounts of the Whitney Plantation indicated it was an important experience. Given that I am here in Louisiana, in large part to be [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><div class="wsite-image wsite-image-border-none " style="padding-top:10px;padding-bottom:10px;margin-left:0;margin-right:0;text-align:center"> <a href='https://photos.app.goo.gl/4rQta8NmrmsVJUEA7'> <img src="http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/uploads/1/2/6/4/126456576/p357.png" alt="Picture" style="width:auto;max-width:100%" /> </a> <div style="display:block;font-size:90%"> Click on image above to see more photos</div> </div></div>  <div class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"><span style="font-family: ".SFUIText"; font-size: 17pt;">A few days ago while we were taking a rest at Essence Fest, Kimberly brought out a pamphlet advertising the Whitney Plantation. She had heard about it previously and had been interested in going for a while. I had not heard of it, nor had I really contemplated going on any tours as part of this excursion, but all of the accounts of the Whitney Plantation indicated it was an important experience. Given that I am here in Louisiana, in large part to better understand the legacy of slavery as part of the US, it was a gift dropped from heaven.</span><br /><span></span></div>  <div>  <!--BLOG_SUMMARY_END--></div>  <div class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"><span style="font-family: ".SFUIText"; font-size: 17pt;">An even bigger gift was Sabrina and Luana coming with me. As we noted afterward, it was not an experience that one really wants to have alone. I was really grateful to have friends with me at the plantation, and someone to talk about it afterward.</span><span style="font-family: ".SFUIText"; font-size: 17pt;"></span><br /><br /><span></span>  <span style="font-family: ".SFUIText"; font-size: 17pt;">The Whitney Plantation was a sugar cane plantation. Sugar was unique in the plantation agricultural worlds because of a 3 month window during which all of the harvesting and importantly all of the production needed to be done. Because cane juice spoils, the sugar had to be processed immediately, on site, which made the plantations, factories as much as they were farms. Enslaved people worked around clock to maximize the production of sugar. The Union Pacific railroad picked it up directly from the plantation. It was notorious for being one of the worst types of work. In one year the Whitney plantation by itself produced 25% of the country&rsquo;s sugar. </span><span style="font-family: ".SFUIText"; font-size: 17pt;"></span><br /><br /><span></span>  <span style="font-family: ".SFUIText"; font-size: 17pt;">The stories that make up the Whitney&rsquo;s foundation are oral accounts from formerly enslaved people. The stories were collected during the works progress administration era by writers (funded by the federal government in the new deal) who realized what would be lost if the last surviving people who had experienced America plantation slavery were not able to share their personal accounts.</span><span style="font-family: ".SFUIText"; font-size: 17pt;"></span><br /><br /><span></span>  <span style="font-family: ".SFUIText"; font-size: 17pt;">The plantation was a collection of both restored structures, not unlike Hawaii&rsquo;s own plantation villages, and solemn and beautiful memorials to the men, women, children who had worked and often died on the plantation, as well as the children and infants born into that life that never made it to adulthood. </span><span style="font-family: ".SFUIText"; font-size: 17pt;"></span><br /><br /><span></span>  <span style="font-family: ".SFUIText"; font-size: 17pt;">It&rsquo;s difficult to capture the shame and sadness that come with confronting American slavery on the site and in the buildings where the suffering took place. A trip that we decided not to take, but might have had the same potential &mdash; with similar perspective of firsthand accounts &mdash; was to the Angola prison, known for many years as America&rsquo;s worst prison. As another Louisiana friend, Jessi Parfait, the archivist for the United Houma Nation shared with me, the prison is sited on what was one a beautiful Houma settlement.</span><span style="font-family: ".SFUIText"; font-size: 17pt;"></span><br /><br /><span></span>  <span style="font-family: ".SFUIText"; font-size: 17pt;">Without drawing away from the shamefulness of the violence our society inflicted on its people, the three of us were in awe of what our ancestors, created, lived through and passed forward. As Sabrina pointed out, even with all that happened, &ldquo;we&rsquo;re still here.&rdquo; That makes me really proud, even though the people who were enslaved at the Whitney were not my direct biological ancestors. I hope that they would be proud of the work we do and the lives we lead today.</span><br /><span></span></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Wetlands and Chemical Plants (Day 6)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/blog/wetlands-and-chemical-plants-day-6]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/blog/wetlands-and-chemical-plants-day-6#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 07:30:08 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/blog/wetlands-and-chemical-plants-day-6</guid><description><![CDATA[       I ended the day at the Vacherie Community Center, coincidentally, right in front of a sign pointing down the street to the Whitney Plantation we visite the day before. Gathered outside were a group of people wearing matching yellow shirts reading, &ldquo;Rise St James&rdquo;, talking into loudspeakers and holding Signs that read &ldquo;no jobs on a dead planet&rdquo; and &ldquo;we stand with students worldwide #climatestrike&rdquo;. The Louisiana Department of Environmental Quality was ho [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><div class="wsite-image wsite-image-border-none " style="padding-top:10px;padding-bottom:10px;margin-left:0;margin-right:0;text-align:center"> <a href='https://photos.app.goo.gl/gVf4RVYkwXEvqnf26'> <img src="http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/uploads/1/2/6/4/126456576/p355.png" alt="Picture" style="width:auto;max-width:100%" /> </a> <div style="display:block;font-size:90%"></div> </div></div>  <div class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"><span style="font-family: ".SFUIText"; font-size: 17pt;">I ended the day at the Vacherie Community Center, coincidentally, right in front of a sign pointing down the street to the Whitney Plantation we visite the day before. Gathered outside were a group of people wearing matching yellow shirts reading, &ldquo;Rise St James&rdquo;, talking into loudspeakers and holding Signs that read &ldquo;no jobs on a dead planet&rdquo; and &ldquo;we stand with students worldwide #climatestrike&rdquo;. The Louisiana Department of Environmental Quality was holding a public meeting about Formosa Chemical&rsquo;s application for an air quality permit. The St. James community is located in what is increasingly known nationally as Cancer Alley, where residents, particularly black communities, suffer increased instances of cancer while elevated levels of toxic pollutants are discharged by the many chemical plants currently situated there along the Mississippi River between Baton Rouge and New Orleans.</span><br /><span></span></div>  <div>  <!--BLOG_SUMMARY_END--></div>  <div class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;"><span>But I started the day on a solo excursion to Lousiana&rsquo;s Bayou Country in Houma. I went to Houma to catch Jonathan Foret, the Executive Director of the South Louisiana wetland discovery center before his late lunch. Jonathan, along with Jessi Parfait was one of two people that I had gotten in contact with before I left Honolulu. Both were connected to so many vital issues, organizations, and work areas, that I wanted to ensure I&rsquo;d have time on the later end of my trip to follow any leads they pointed out. Jessi, had for example, directed me to both the LDEQ hearing above and the New Orleans People&rsquo;s assembly meeting that I had hoped to join a few days later on Thursday night.</span><br /><br /><span>While Jonathan and I were sitting in his office chatting, he got news that the funding for the first phase of construction of the discovery center was on the agenda for the bond commission, a critical step that might have them breaking ground and starting construction by the end of the year. Having lived through state funding processes and currently living through a monster construction project I was really happy for him and for SWLDC! </span><br /><br /><span>We didn&rsquo;t have too much time to chat, but I had lots of questions about the Bayou and the wetlands and Jonathan agreed to take me out on a driving tour of the Bayou a few days later on Thursday. Part of the thinking was that it looked like there was a storm brewing on the gulf and the tour might be more viable Thursday than Friday. </span><br /><br /><span>Jonathan&rsquo;s lunch was with a woman who helped create and administer a program called LASAFE which trained and developed leaders already embedded and respected in community to facilitate community conversations. She was another person I wanted to meet very much, but I was committed to a 2:00 back in New Orleans to have a chat with Mama Denise Graves of the Congo Square Preservation Society.</span><br /><br /><span>My meeting with Mama Denise was full of incredible stories of doing grassroots organizing, building power in communities, subverting and leveraging institutional positions, and personal challenges to find and articulate my values. It was that last one that hit home especially for me. I have always considered myself a principled person... but at that moment, (and in this one), I could not tell you what my values are or why I don&rsquo;t have that answer. </span><br /><br /><span>Mama shared a bit about her own ongoing spiritual journey and study of various forms of spirituality, healing, and tradition. She was on her way to England and Ireland to explore Celtic traditions and had been trying to make her way to Vietnam as well. She reminded me of Nana Veary in the diversity of her pursuit, despite her clear mastery of many aspects of spirituality (Mama Denise lead an incredible and fluent offering of libations to ancestors during the Congo Square drumming circle). </span><br /><br /><span>Mama shared about her 2 biological and 5 non biological children. Some of the stories were sad, all of them were remarkable. Reflections on parenthood and having kids has been a theme of this trip. I am understanding the relationship between values, children, and humanness in ways I never did previously.</span><br /><br /><span>Right afterwards I headed up to Vacherie for the community meeting. I got there pretty early, and figured something was up when I saw photographers, two sheriffs trucks and armed officers (one with a beautifully detailed tattoo sleeve of feathers and fur - who seemed to appreciate the compliment when I told her I thought so). I got there at the same time as two conspicuously dressed gentlemen wearing sports coats and slacks, looking a bit like my stereotype of souther plantation owners. They never spoke in the meeting, but shook a lot of hands and received a few snarky comments from one of the lead activists.</span><br /><br /><span>Jessi warned me that I might be disgusted with how the meeting was run. As a city employee, having been a part of many public meetings where the community was angry at my agency, I thought I might understand where the LDEQ was coming from. Jessi was right.</span><br /><br /><span>It was an upsetting display of an almost entirely black community all, unanimously expressing their strong rejection of this project and their anger and hurt about how their community has suffered. Meanwhile, every testimonial in support of the project came from a person that was white and that did not live in the community &mdash; including the Parish Concilmember our president, I forget which, who was ostensible representing the community. The testifies were passionate and moving and honest and proud and resilient. They inspired support from students around the country that came to that meeting there in Vacherie. The final decision was not going to be made at that meeting, but I suspect that the resistance was not going to be enough.</span></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Congo Square (Day 4)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/blog/congo-square-day-4]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/blog/congo-square-day-4#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 05:48:54 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/blog/congo-square-day-4</guid><description><![CDATA[    Click the image to see all photos   A few weekends ago, my friend Kevin at KVIBE called me up and said the boys were going to Mokauea island to do a reef cleanup and asked if Tori and I wanted to go. I had wanted to visit KVIBE and sit in on one of their circles as preparation for this trip. I was not able to do that, but I realize now that what I needed to bring with me came from that experience at Mauli Ola and Mokauea. One of the many things that I learned that day are that Hawaiian heiau [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><div class="wsite-image wsite-image-border-none " style="padding-top:10px;padding-bottom:10px;margin-left:0;margin-right:0;text-align:center"> <a href='https://photos.app.goo.gl/9xbYWruvtZuhNjb36'> <img src="http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/uploads/1/2/6/4/126456576/p350.png" alt="Picture" style="width:auto;max-width:100%" /> </a> <div style="display:block;font-size:90%">Click the image to see all photos</div> </div></div>  <div class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;">A few weekends ago, my friend Kevin at KVIBE called me up and said the boys were going to Mokauea island to do a reef cleanup and asked if Tori and I wanted to go. I had wanted to visit KVIBE and sit in on one of their circles as preparation for this trip. I was not able to do that, but I realize now that what I needed to bring with me came from that experience at Mauli Ola and Mokauea. One of the many things that I learned that day are that Hawaiian heiau (sacred alters) are not structures, but sites. It is the site that is sacred, not what is on the site. So they can&rsquo;t be moved. Moreover, all of the heiau are connected. Congo Square, is in my opinion, one of the most sacred heiau in the world, just not visited primarily by hawaiians and not on the hawaiian islands.<br /></div>  <div>  <!--BLOG_SUMMARY_END--></div>  <div class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;">Congo Square is in Louis Armstrong park in the Treme neighborhood of New Orleans. Treme is recognized as America&rsquo;s oldest black neighborhood. The history of Congo Square is fascinating, rich, and of great importance. My description will not do it justice and I encourage everyone reading this to learn as much as you can about it. It is on located at a site known to be sacred to the Houma tribe of indigenous people and during the times when it received the name Congo Square, it was a place where enslaved people were allowed to gather unsupervised and participate in their cultural practices from Africa. The cultural celebration it enabled can, as Wynton Marsalis points out, be traced forward into every form of American music today.<br /><br />the Congo Square preservation society convenes drumming circles every Sunday afternoon. It was one of the things I was most eager to experience, and I wasn&rsquo;t sure exactly when it would happen when I first arrived in New Orleans. I stayed in a hotel in Treme just to be nearby. Luckily, we ran into Mama Denise of the Congo Square Preservation Society at the conclusion of the Maafa on the previous day and she was able to tell us the exact time.<br /><br />I arrived in Congo Square a little early to essentially an empty park. After waiting about 30 minutes after it was supposed to start, I began to lose hope about it happening. The a truck drove up onto the stones, and another one pulled up right behind it. People started setting up little chairs, and I just about ran over to the other side of the square where they were.<br /><br />As I type this, my palms still feel tender from where they hit the rims of the drums, a few hundred (maybe a thousand?) times. They got especially tender after I started hitting the drum for real - after having it taken away and getting called out for faking it. When I arrived, the sun was high in the sky and the whole day was ahead of me. By the time I left after chatting with people and taking some photos, a guard on a golf cart had to whistle at me and tell me to leave because the park was closing.<br /><br />To to say that drumming with the Congo preservation society was a spiritual experience does not capture to me in my own mind what happened to me there. Or maybe it just elevates my understanding of what a spiritual experience really is. Between dancing and drumming, thinking and feeling, I connected to something powerful. I wasn&rsquo;t always connected to it, in fact, it was probably only a tiny fraction of my time there. But I got there a few times, and got a taste for who I needed to be to find it.<br /><br /><span style="-webkit-text-size-adjust: 100%; background-color: transparent;">&#8203;At at one point after my first drum had been withdrawn and the circle was really getting going, Mama Denise had me move into the middle of the circle and dance. I had been a part of the circle the entire time, even when I was not drumming. So I was always close to it. But on the perimeter. At that particular time, feeling the middle of the circle (was it also responding to me dancing?) was a completely different thing at a completely different level. Looking back at it now, feeling that moment over again, I was connected, like a beam of light through the middle of the earth to all of the heiau in Hawaii. I was scared to stay in it too long, afraid of taking up too much space. But I wish I had been there longer.</span><br /></div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[In Search of Maafa and Political Leadership (Day 3)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/blog/chasing-maafa-and-political-inspiration]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/blog/chasing-maafa-and-political-inspiration#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 05:40:39 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/blog/chasing-maafa-and-political-inspiration</guid><description><![CDATA[     Click image to see all photos   I was determined to do a better job of making it to the Essence Fest Power Conference events on my second time around. I had figured out parking and new the conference layout. Plus today, four presidential candidates were going to be talking story with interviewers on stage. Where else would you get to see the equivalent of a presidential debate, but with time to focus on each individual candidate?! Kamala Harris, who I was especially excited to see with her  [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><div class="wsite-image wsite-image-border-none " style="padding-top:10px;padding-bottom:10px;margin-left:0;margin-right:0;text-align:center"> <a href='https://photos.app.goo.gl/UKWZTuGNzVyf9dZo7'> <img src="http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/uploads/1/2/6/4/126456576/p346.png" alt="Picture" style="width:auto;max-width:100%" /> </a> <div style="display:block;font-size:90%"> Click image to see all photos</div> </div></div>  <div class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;">I was determined to do a better job of making it to the Essence Fest Power Conference events on my second time around. I had figured out parking and new the conference layout. Plus today, four presidential candidates were going to be talking story with interviewers on stage. Where else would you get to see the equivalent of a presidential debate, but with time to focus on each individual candidate?! Kamala Harris, who I was especially excited to see with her post-debate lift, was the first candidate on deck. And I was all set to get to the stage on time. Then I got this text from Kim:<br /></div>  <blockquote style="text-align:left;">Did you know there is a Maafa ceremony this morning? Honoring the enslaved Africans who died here. At Louis Armstrong Park. Ends there at 11:00</blockquote>  <div>  <!--BLOG_SUMMARY_END--></div>  <div class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;">Well, I guess we&rsquo;e doing that. Kamala will have to wait for another day.<br /><br />I got the text around 9:00 and the Maafa actually started around 7:00 and by the time we got up and out, it was almost 11:00. Some really resourceful and well-placed questions, put us hot on their tail. &ldquo;They typically walk down from the chapel to the river.&rdquo; &ldquo;They just passed here. you might be able to catch up&rdquo;.<br /><br />We caught up just as the group was breaking up. Not unlike the previous day, I was disappointed. This was a really special opportunity and we were so close to getting to see this thing, that happens only once a year and happened to be on a day we were there. And kamala was waiting back at the convention center and we would not have made it back there in time.<br /><br />We decided to take the opportunity to walk around that part of t he riverfront - Plaza de Armas (near cafe du Monde). That turned out to be an excellent idea. There were still a few people who had been with the Maafa who had not departed yet, we got to talk to a couple, Mama Denise and Anita, who were very involved in the Congo Preservation Society. In addition to learning about the Congo square drumming circle happening the next day, we also got some beautiful history of the event, and what it was dedicated to.<br /><br />We we had several interesting conversations with people on the waterfront, including a man who lost everything in Katrina and had been on the riverfront since then (he said to google &ldquo;private jet needs fuel&rdquo; and we could always find photos of him). I had a long conversation with a group of passionate Hebrew Israelites that was alternately uncomfortable and really engaging and generous. We visited a local artist who did beautiful expressive work with themes celebrating people of color.<br /><br />We got back to the convention center in time to catch the end of an enormous crowd cheering Maxine Waters, listen to Elizabeth Warren tell moving stories about her own struggles as a mother, and get a close up view of the incredible moral clarity and passion powering representative Ilhan Omar. These conversations were 5-10minutes, maybe 15minutes max.  But each took on the incredible task of connecting with a crowd, to various degrees of succes... but watching how they work was a marvel.<br /><br />Then at 9:40PM sitting in nosebleed seats of a sold out superdome, I got to be a part of a conversation with Michelle Obama. We were not physically close,  but she was so real, so genuine, so unfiltered... it felt like it. Cut loose a bit from the pressures of the presidency and her job as First Lady, she seemed a little more open, and it felt like she was talking to me &mdash; and I think there were thousands of other people in the room who would agree with me. She was visibly emotional when talking about her dad, risk-taking when talking about marriage and parenting. <br /><br />I was furiously attempting to take notes on my iPhone, and just as she was hitting her most resonant point, my phone, after a long day of service, finally died. So I just had to remember it. In response to a question from the moderator that it seemed like she and Barrack were living their best life, and that we were all happy for them. She responded that, the Obamas are going to be fine. But it doesn&rsquo;t feel so good when they know that there are lots of people in this country that aren&rsquo;t doing fine. They didn&rsquo;t work on Obamacare because they needed health care. They didn&rsquo;t because millions of Americans did. So that&rsquo;s the part that&rsquo;s hard. They&rsquo;ll be living their best life when everyone is living their best life. We don&rsquo;t win unless we all win. That&rsquo;s a liberation message that makes sense to me.</div>  <blockquote style="text-align:left;"><br /><br />If you have come here to help me, you are wasting your time.<br />But if you have come because your liberation is bound up with mine, then let us work together.<br />- <span style="color:rgb(34, 34, 34)">Aboriginal activists group, Queensland, 1970s</span></blockquote>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[ESSENCE Festival (Day 2)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/blog/essence-festival-day-1]]></link><comments><![CDATA[http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/blog/essence-festival-day-1#comments]]></comments><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 05:39:58 GMT</pubDate><category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/blog/essence-festival-day-1</guid><description><![CDATA[    Click image to see all photos   I was most excited to visit the &ldquo;Power Conference&rdquo; stage at Essence Fest where black artists and leaders share inspiration, ideas, and stories about changing the world. On the early afternoon agenda were panels with titles like: &ldquo;The Black Effect: How our culture dictates what is next from creation to consumption&rdquo; and &ldquo;For colored girls who have considered politics&rdquo;. I was especially interested in &ldquo;Breaking the cycle o [...] ]]></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><div class="wsite-image wsite-image-border-none " style="padding-top:10px;padding-bottom:10px;margin-left:0;margin-right:0;text-align:center"> <a href='https://photos.app.goo.gl/jndBMvfBCeTMVN5v5'> <img src="http://www.libertyandbelongingus.com/uploads/1/2/6/4/126456576/p44.png" alt="Picture" style="width:auto;max-width:100%" /> </a> <div style="display:block;font-size:90%">Click image to see all photos</div> </div></div>  <div class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;">I was most excited to visit the &ldquo;Power Conference&rdquo; stage at Essence Fest where black artists and leaders share inspiration, ideas, and stories about changing the world. On the early afternoon agenda were panels with titles like: &ldquo;The Black Effect: How our culture dictates what is next from creation to consumption&rdquo; and &ldquo;For colored girls who have considered politics&rdquo;. I was especially interested in &ldquo;Breaking the cycle of silence to heal our communities&rdquo; with Terry Crews and Common. I missed them all. </div>  <div>  <!--BLOG_SUMMARY_END--></div>  <div class="paragraph" style="text-align:left;">Between the parking insanity (anticipated but nevertheless completely helpless against) and the enormity of the conference (unanticipated and completely unprepared for) I was about an hour and a half later than the 4 hour late start I was already dealing with. I tried to take the sage advice of my new friend Sabrina and tell myself that I was exactly where I was supposed to be, but the hot sun and getting frustratingly lost in New Orleans&rsquo;s theme-park sized convention center made it difficult.<br /><br />What made it easier was the fact that Essence Fest was straight up incredible. As a frequenter of conference type gatherings and the occasional festival, the rest of the gathering world can learn a lot from how black folks get together for Essence fest. In no particular order, some of the things that stood out to me #1 families attending. Legit multigenerational, all ages, keiki to kupuna. #2 a dedication to style and beauty that was also so various #3 the spectacle #4 the awesome T-shirt&rsquo;s (my favorite was on a man and read: Dear Police, I am a white woman&rdquo;). <span>I love the way the world looks and feels at Essence. And it has not ever felt like that to me before.</span><br /><br /><span>in so many ways I cannot believe my own dumb luck. I planned my trip around a moon cycle and an unrelated political statement. In any year, going to this festival would have been a once in a lifetime kind of opportunity. In this particular year on this learning excursion about the legacy of America&rsquo;s treatment of race, it is surreal.</span><br /><br /><span>Essence fest is huge. Unfathomably so. I recommend learning about it and tracking the conversations and performance there. For me, it helped me stay sane to focus on the Power Conference. When I eventually did get there, i caught some amazing, rich and challenging conversations.</span><br /><br /><span>One called #blackdadsmatter was an emotional experience for me - I was in tears as I remembered something that I forgot almost 15 years ago. How much I want to be a father. Those men are who I want to be as a dad. I also got to see Ava Duvernay, a voice in film that I am in awe of, talk about her work telling stories of the incareral state. Each of these panels warrants a blog post of its own. Suffice it to say, by the end of the day it was no longer hard to convince myself that I was exactly where I was supposed to be.</span></div>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>