<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<urlset xmlns="http://www.sitemaps.org/schemas/sitemap/0.9" xmlns:image="http://www.google.com/schemas/sitemap-image/1.1">
  <url>
    <loc>https://www.bentoriwedding.com/home</loc>
    <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
    <priority>1.0</priority>
    <lastmod>2019-08-13</lastmod>
    <image:image>
      <image:loc>https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5d118268370a230001b4b030/t/5d1d3c8699ed3b00012cc251/1565674948113/Honolulu5x7.jpg</image:loc>
      <image:title>Home - Outrigger Canoe Club</image:title>
    </image:image>
    <image:image>
      <image:loc>https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5d118268370a230001b4b030/t/5d1d39a9ae39c800013cf695/1563258941670/Parma5x7.jpg</image:loc>
      <image:title>Home - Castello di Tabiano</image:title>
    </image:image>
    <image:image>
      <image:loc>https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5d118268370a230001b4b030/t/5d1d3a52bfecef0001e29173/1563258922546/Napa5x7.jpg</image:loc>
      <image:title>Home - Cuvaison Winery</image:title>
    </image:image>
    <image:image>
      <image:loc>https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5d118268370a230001b4b030/t/5d1d3c0feaad050001663121/1562207408823/Disney5x7.jpg</image:loc>
      <image:title>Home - Downtown Disney</image:title>
    </image:image>
    <image:image>
      <image:loc>https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5d118268370a230001b4b030/t/5d1d3b3a99ed3b00012cae53/1563258781409/Border_5x7.jpg</image:loc>
      <image:title>Home - Rio Grande Valley</image:title>
      <image:caption>Border Theatre</image:caption>
    </image:image>
    <image:image>
      <image:loc>https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5d118268370a230001b4b030/t/5d50aa438c37e00001924f1c/1565567673403/Encore5x7.jpg</image:loc>
      <image:title>Home - Encore Saloon</image:title>
    </image:image>
    <image:image>
      <image:loc>https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5d118268370a230001b4b030/t/5d1d3a37614f410001de8c22/1562207305675/Ogden5x7.jpg</image:loc>
      <image:title>Home - Historic 25th Street</image:title>
    </image:image>
  </url>
  <url>
    <loc>https://www.bentoriwedding.com/ogden</loc>
    <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
    <priority>0.75</priority>
    <lastmod>2019-08-26</lastmod>
    <image:image>
      <image:loc>https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5d118268370a230001b4b030/t/5d1d6c87345aa60001ca9f01/1562439228708/Ogden5x7.jpg</image:loc>
      <image:title>Ogden - Historic 25th Street</image:title>
      <image:caption>Watched over by the majestic Wasatch Mountains, Victoria Dawn Larson grew up in a pink brick house on Winchester lane in Ogden, Utah. Raised by Pam and Keith Larson, the most loving of parents, growing up in Ogden was full of delights — the greatest snow on earth; warm summer nights; sweet peaches, and the freshest ingredients for tomato sandwiches. Historic Ogden — the city that joined transcontinental railroads. 25th Street was a backdrop for the development of the west, just 50 miles from the Golden Spike and about 100 miles from where Tori’s great-great-great grandfather built Two Pony Express Stations. More important for this occasion is the role 25th street played in Tori’s history. Site of lunches with friends and mother daughter afternoons spent together. That street was just around the corner from the magic pink castle on Winchester Lane.</image:caption>
    </image:image>
  </url>
  <url>
    <loc>https://www.bentoriwedding.com/disney</loc>
    <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
    <priority>0.75</priority>
    <lastmod>2019-07-26</lastmod>
    <image:image>
      <image:loc>https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5d118268370a230001b4b030/t/5d1d6ce7bfecef0001e591b0/1562403716663/Disney5x7.jpg</image:loc>
      <image:title>Downtown Disney - Downtown Disney</image:title>
      <image:caption>In 1968, The Semense family moved from the Philippines to Long Beach, California, where Ben and the Trevino family spent many happy summers and holidays. From their home in Utah, Tori and Keith Larson would steal away to Anaheim for father daughter Disneyland adventures. The family and friends Ben and Tori have in Southern California are both the people they come from and people they come back to — whose open, knowing arms make the voyage to someplace new possible. Meanwhile, Disneyland is a reminder of a sincere and shared belief in the possibility of the happiest place on earth, one that is especially happy when filled with the people you love.</image:caption>
    </image:image>
  </url>
  <url>
    <loc>https://www.bentoriwedding.com/napa</loc>
    <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
    <priority>0.75</priority>
    <lastmod>2019-07-26</lastmod>
    <image:image>
      <image:loc>https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5d118268370a230001b4b030/t/5d1d6d40fe4a970001fa8c03/1562403789393/Napa5x7.jpg</image:loc>
      <image:title>Cuvaison WInery - Cuvaison Winery</image:title>
      <image:caption>Ben’s college years and early career were spent in the Bay Area. Before that, the Bay was reserved for summers visiting family. Tori similarly spent time visiting her sister and brother-in-law’s home in Alameda. Many of their best friends created homes up and down Northern California and opportunities to visit are never short of happy reunions. More recently, the rolling hills of Napa, and specifically the serenity of Cuvaison have provided a special place for Ben and Tori to retreat and connect — the chance to step away from a daily routine and remember who they are, what they are doing, and who they are doing it with. Their friends in the Bay and up the west coast offer a similar retreat, one of belonging. They are brilliant, thoughtful inspirations — constantly introducing them to new things in new places, never needing them to be anyone other than who they are.</image:caption>
    </image:image>
  </url>
  <url>
    <loc>https://www.bentoriwedding.com/honolulu</loc>
    <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
    <priority>0.75</priority>
    <lastmod>2019-07-26</lastmod>
    <image:image>
      <image:loc>https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5d118268370a230001b4b030/t/5d1d6dac8df1e600013af84c/1565566989600/Honolulu5x7.jpg</image:loc>
      <image:title>New Page - Outrigger Canoe Club</image:title>
      <image:caption>“Oh they were so happy, To finally meet above the sea All together now , their lava grew and grew No longer are they all alone, With Aloha as their new home…” Some 2000 miles from the nearest continental land, Ben and Tori met on January 29, 2016 in the Ocean Room at the Outrigger Canoe Club. Tori moved to Lahaina Maui in June of 2016. Ben followed her there a week later and they’ve been inseparable ever since. Ben and Tori are endlessly inspired by Hawaii and the people who they share a home with here. Their marriage, a commitment to each other, is a commitment to hana alongside their ohana and malama the place that brought them together. “…And when you go and visit them this is what they sing I have a dream I hope it will come true That you will grow old with me, and I will grow old with you We thank the earth, sea, and the sky we thank too I lava you”</image:caption>
    </image:image>
  </url>
  <url>
    <loc>https://www.bentoriwedding.com/parma</loc>
    <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
    <priority>0.75</priority>
    <lastmod>2019-07-30</lastmod>
    <image:image>
      <image:loc>https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5d118268370a230001b4b030/t/5d1d6e15fe4a970001fa97cd/1562403211554/</image:loc>
      <image:title>Parma - Castello di Tabiano</image:title>
      <image:caption>Parma, Italy was founded as a Roman colony in 183 BC. When Ben and Tori arrive in Parma, it will be the first time either of them has ever set foot there. Their marriage certificate will be both a part of a 2000 year history, and a symbol of a new adventure and unknown territory. Beautiful, rustic Parma will serve as the final departure point for Ben and Tori’s journey as partners and the kickoff to the project of building a life together. Not sure what they will encounter along the way or what problems they will need to solve. But they know they will need a lot of assistance — from the people, places and traditions that got them here, and from those friends and family that can meet them along the way. More than anything, they are excited to set off together! And are endlessly grateful for confidence, inspiration, love, and aloha they receive from the special places and people in their lives.</image:caption>
    </image:image>
  </url>
  <url>
    <loc>https://www.bentoriwedding.com/rsvp-parma</loc>
    <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
    <priority>0.75</priority>
    <lastmod>2019-07-26</lastmod>
  </url>
  <url>
    <loc>https://www.bentoriwedding.com/rgv</loc>
    <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
    <priority>0.75</priority>
    <lastmod>2019-07-26</lastmod>
    <image:image>
      <image:loc>https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5d118268370a230001b4b030/t/5d20f18f1407cc00018c9edd/1562440108905/San-Juan_tonight%27s-program-smaller.jpg</image:loc>
      <image:title>Border Theater - The Rio Grande Valley</image:title>
      <image:caption>Six generations ago, Gregorio and Refugia Trevino settled their family in the Rio Grande Valley. Their five children—Luisa, Guadalupe, Eduvijes, Maria, and Felicitas gave rise to a family that now includes over 200 children, grandchildren, great grandchildren, and great great grandchildren, including one Benjamin Eduardo Trevino. In his hometown of San Juan, along the Texas/Mexico border, he was blessed with family as well as a proud Mexican heritage. Growing up there were two things Ben spent countless hours doing. One was going to the movies with his parents Rodolfo and Maria Teresa, and his siblings, Emerito, Laura, and Felicitas — theaters today still remind him of family and feel like home. The other was making tortillas with his Aunt Mary. This was a gift he shared with Tori during the first meal they ever made together and is now one of their favorite ways to spend Sundays. This tradition is something they hope to pass along to their own kids no matter where they grow up.</image:caption>
    </image:image>
  </url>
  <url>
    <loc>https://www.bentoriwedding.com/things-to-do-parma</loc>
    <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
    <priority>0.75</priority>
    <lastmod>2019-07-30</lastmod>
  </url>
  <url>
    <loc>https://www.bentoriwedding.com/chinatown</loc>
    <changefreq>daily</changefreq>
    <priority>0.75</priority>
    <lastmod>2019-08-11</lastmod>
    <image:image>
      <image:loc>https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5d118268370a230001b4b030/t/5d50a867e6a2b000010fe42f/1565567087223/Encore5x7.jpg</image:loc>
      <image:title>Chinatown - Encore Saloon</image:title>
      <image:caption>The 4th oldest Chinatown in the US, the district has been witness to nearly 150 years of Honolulu’s history. That history includes a handful of moments featuring Ben and Tori in significant points in their own history. Ben’s love of cinemas found a home the Hawaii Theatre Centre in his first week in Honolulu, volunteering for the Hawaii International Film Festival. Years later, Tori was working out of the R.O.C. coworking space just above Encore Saloon, helping to plan the event where they met. Just before she moved to Maui when neither of them was quite sure what was going to happen, they celebrated Tori’s birthday together at Tchin Tchin. Today both Ben and Tori work downtown, and Chinatown — just a stones throw away — has served as a place to celebrate milestones and achievements, cook up new projects, and enjoy some late night fellowship with cherished coworkers, collaborators, and friends. It is getting to work alongside these people every day that fills their life and partnership in Hawaii with meaning. If they end up as part of Chinatown’s memory, they hope it is for the people and work they were so invested in.</image:caption>
    </image:image>
  </url>
</urlset>

